<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[User group for Viennese rubyists]]></title>
  <link href="http://vienna-rb.at/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://vienna-rb.at/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-13T16:57:55+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://vienna-rb.at/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[vienna.rb team]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[viennarb@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The slides of our second meetup are online]]></title>
    <link href="http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/04/13/the-slides-of-our-second-meetup-are-online/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-13T17:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/04/13/the-slides-of-our-second-meetup-are-online</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>ALL the slides</h2>

<p>Hi there, we just pushed the slides of the second meetup to our <a href="https://github.com/vienna-rb/slides">repository</a>. Feel free to check them out.</p>

<h5>Floor Drees, introducing the Coders without Borders project</h5>

<h5>Gerald Bauer on his beer.db and world.db gem</h5>

<h5>Tomáš Kramár on &#8216;open&#8217; data in Slovakia</h5>

<h5>Anton Bangratz opened up his big o&#8217; bag of tricks</h5>

<p>Like what you see? Join us for our next <a href="http://www.meetup.com/vienna-rb/events/102695522/">meetup</a> on May the 9th at Sektor5!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New about page]]></title>
    <link href="http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/03/27/new-about-page/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-27T20:12:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/03/27/new-about-page</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The vienna.rb class</h2>

<p>We just added a new page to the blog. The <a href="http://vienna-rb.at/about">about</a> page contains a bit more information about what we do, where we do it and who we are. It also is a functioning Ruby class.</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/5257111.js?file=irb_test'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>→ curl -o vienna.rb https://gist.github.com/pxlpnk/5257111/raw/a577da6be4807daa4b4a2751659d100f7d1ba9f6/vienna.rb 

→ irb -r &quot;./vienna.rb&quot;

&gt;&gt; v = Vienna.new
=&gt; The next vienna.rb takes place at sektor5 Siebenbrunnengasse 44, 1050 Wien and starts at 2013-04-12 18:00:00 +0100. For more see: http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/03/19/second-meetup-to-take-place-at-co-working-space-sektor5/

&gt;&gt; v.where?
=&gt; #&lt;struct Struct::Location name=&quot;sektor5&quot;, address=&quot;Siebenbrunnengasse 44, 1050 Wien&quot;, details=nil&gt;

&gt;&gt; v.when?
=&gt; 2013-04-12 18:00:00 +0100

&gt;&gt; v.what_and_why?
=&gt; #&lt;URI::HTTP:0x007fc26983c9c0 URL:http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/03/19/second-meetup-to-take-place-at-co-working-space-sektor5/&gt;

&gt;&gt; v.who?
=&gt; {&quot;Floor Drees&quot;=&gt;&quot;@floordrees&quot;, &quot;Anton Bangratz&quot;=&gt;&quot;@tony_xpro&quot;, &quot;Andreas Tiefenthaler&quot;=&gt;&quot;@pxlpnk&quot;}

&gt;&gt; v.version
=&gt; &quot;v0.0.3 - 2013-03-27 19:39&quot;

&gt;&gt; puts v 
The next vienna.rb takes place at sektor5 Siebenbrunnengasse 44, 1050 Wien and starts at 2013-04-12 18:00:00 +0100. For more see: http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/03/19/second-meetup-to-take-place-at-co-working-space-sektor5/
=&gt; nil
</code></pre></noscript></div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The slides of our first meetup are online]]></title>
    <link href="http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/03/26/the-slides-of-our-first-meetup-are-online/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-26T22:54:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/03/26/the-slides-of-our-first-meetup-are-online</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Slides slides slides</h2>

<p>Hey there folks, we just pushed the slides of our very first meetup to our <a href="https://github.com/vienna-rb/slides">repository</a>. Feel free to check them out even if you weren&#8217;t there. If you like what you see, join us for our next <a href="http://www.meetup.com/vienna-rb/events/102695402/">meetup</a> on April the 12th at Sektor 5.</p>

<p>In the future we plan to collect and publish the slides so you won&#8217;t miss anything if you can&#8217;t make it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rubyslava #26 - Ruby Meet Up in Bratislava]]></title>
    <link href="http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/03/22/rubyslava-number-26-ruby-meet-up-in-bratislava/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-22T18:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/03/22/rubyslava-number-26-ruby-meet-up-in-bratislava</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Dobrý večer - good evening!</h2>

<p>Last week, Andy (<a href="https:/twitter.com/pxlpnk">@pxlpnk</a>) and me decided to visit the Rubyslava event - because <a href="http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/02/14/vienna-dot-rb-brings-rubyists-together/">they already visited and helped to start off the first vienna.rb meetup</a> - and we wanted to return the favour. Yes, and we are actually both extremely curious and wanted to learn some things first hand.</p>

<p>After a short train and bus ride we reached our destination, the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Kaf%C3%A9-Nervosa/194088387296884">Kafé Nervosa</a>. As a location, I found it very much to my liking: pizza, beer, a beamer and a PA system. When we arrived, it was already well filled with people, and they still kept on coming in. Later we would learn that this was a record breaking evening in that regard.</p>

<p>For starting off, we were treated with an interesting overview of techniques and tools that help you <strong>saving time</strong>, presented by <a href="https://twitter.com/milan_novota">Milan Novota</a> of <a href="http://subteca.com/">Subteca</a>. Interestingly enough, the slides were in english, but the talk wasn&#8217;t - I could follow it, though, even if we weren&#8217;t really reacting appropriately to certain questions for the audience. And Milan, I know you weren&#8217;t aware that the two of us weren&#8217;t able to follow every word, the apology really wasn&#8217;t necessary. I enjoyed the fact that a lot of the stuff presented (like the pomodoro technique, tmux, zsh, tdd, git, &#8230;) is already part of our work repertoire. The short chat afterwards was also really interesting and enlightening, and I would love to support any effort of teaching more people stuff that I know.</p>

<p>Oh, and thanks for the free beer :)</p>

<p>The next talk was really interesting for me personally - Ján Lunter of Innovatrics presented interesting ways of using Ruby/RoR in a non-standard way - in embedded systems, gathering and comparing biometric data. I got that having such a huge framework running on a PC or Intel Server is quite different to having it running on a small ARM based appliance. Kudos for sailing those rough waters and succeeding!</p>

<p>It didn&#8217;t stop there at all, though. The next topic was presented by <a href="https://twitter.com/petrbela">Petr Bela</a>: a short introduction to <a href="http://angularjs.org/">AngularJS</a> and how it is being used to power <a href="http://www.kdyjedes.cz/">Kdyjedeš</a>. Petr, sorry for springing a slew on questions of you immediately - and then again in the horrible mix of dialects I use to sprinkle my English violently with. And thanks for your patience with me - I got a good idea what I will use AngularJS for soon. I will definitely try it, and the other things you presented.</p>

<p>After those presentations, we had a lot of fun talking to people about various aspects of ruby, RoR and related topics. And had a second beer. Maybe a third &#8230;</p>

<p>It was a pity that we had to leave then to catch the train back to Vienna in time. And while I can not promise that I will visit every time, I definitely will come over every once in a while, to meet, greet and learn.</p>

<p>Thanks for having us!</p>

<p>Andy &amp; tony</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Second meetup to take place at co-working space Sektor5]]></title>
    <link href="http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/03/19/second-meetup-to-take-place-at-co-working-space-sektor5/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-19T19:26:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/03/19/second-meetup-to-take-place-at-co-working-space-sektor5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Ruby developers and Rails aficionados once more meet in Austria’s capital</h3>

<p>After a full house for the first vienna.rb meetup in March the organizing team moves to co-working space <a href="http://sektor5.at/">Sektor5</a> (Siebenbrunnengasse 44, Vienna) for their next developer get-together. Friday, April the 12th they will combine TGIF and meeting like minded people. Vienna.rb meetups are open to both experienced Ruby developers and people that are new to programming.</p>

<blockquote><p>RoR is used by many to bring their ideas online, to turn their visions into products and businesses. That&#8217;s awesome and we&#8217;re glad to be hosting vienna.rb here at sektor5, supporting the cause to bring likeminded Rubyists together!</p><footer><strong>Yves Schultz</strong> <cite>Founder of Sektor 5</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>The meetup is sponsored by <a href="http://radarservices.com/">RadarServices</a>. Christian Polster, Head of Strategy &amp; Finance on why RadarServices supports
vienna.rb:</p>

<blockquote><p>We believe that vienna.rb is the ideal opportunity for all current and future Rubyists to exchange knowledge and best practises. Thereby the enthusiasm for RoR is spread in the community and it helps companies like us to be able to implement the ideas for products and services in an ideal way.</p><footer><strong>Christian Polster</strong> <cite>RadarServices GmbH</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>The vienna.rb team is collecting topics for lightning talks from their community. The topics so far - Speeding up tests,
Rails 4 preview - make for an interesting evening of knowledge exchanging and networking. The sponsors and host are
encouraged to take part in the event or even take on a lightning talk themselves.</p>

<p>The next edition is planned for the 9th of May. For more information regarding the program, please visit <a href="http://meetup.com/vienna-rb">viennarb on meetup</a> or follow <a href="https://twitter.com/viennarb">@viennarb</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[vienna.rb brings rubyists together]]></title>
    <link href="http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/02/14/vienna-dot-rb-brings-rubyists-together/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-14T16:25:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://vienna-rb.at/blog/2013/02/14/vienna-dot-rb-brings-rubyists-together</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Ruby developers and Rails aficionados meet in Austria&#8217;s capital</h3>

<p>On Thursday, March the 7th,  Rails and Ruby developers will exchange their workspaces to meet fellow engineers to discuss their favorite language. Andreas Tiefenthaler, Anton Bangratz and Floor Drees initiated these &#8216;user group meetups&#8217;, excited to meet like minded people. The vienna.rb meetups are open to both experienced Ruby developers and people that are new to programming.</p>

<p>The first meetup will take place at the <a href="http://platogo.com/">platogo.com</a> office. Jakob Sommerhuber, Rails developer and co-founder of Platogo: <em>&#8220;We&#8217;d love to host the event in the cozy atmosphere of our office (free drinks included)!  We&#8217;re really looking forward to taking part in some interesting talks and meeting like-minded developers from Vienna.&#8221;</em></p>

<p>The meetup is sponsored by <a href="http://mjam.at/">Mjam.at</a>, who&#8217;ll provide pizzas for the participants. The sponsors and host are encouraged to take part in the event or even take on a lightning talk themselves.</p>

<p>The vienna.rb team is collecting topics for lightning talks from their young community. The topics; the recent security issues in Rails, testing in Ruby and RoR and &#8216;benchmarking Ruby&#8217;, make for an interesting evening of knowledge exchanging and networking.</p>

<p>Rubyslava, organizing Ruby user group meetups in Bratislava, helped kickstart the Ruby community in Vienna offering their experience and support setting up the first 3 vienna.rb sessions. The next editions are planned for Thursday April the 11th and the 9th of May.</p>

<p>For more information regarding the program, please visit <a href="http://meetup.com/vienna-rb">viennarb on meetup</a> or follow <a href="https://twitter.com/viennarb">@viennarb</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
